Solomon Schechter Day School Collection 0007.003.005a
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
Solomon Schechter Day School
1971-2012
0007.003.005a
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
1.0 Cubic feet 2 boxes
The Solomon Schechter Day School was founded by a group of Conservative rabbis, parents, and educators in 1971. The school initially provided an extensive Judaic curriculum in addition to a full standard academic program for children in Kindergarten through grade six. Originally housed in Emanuel Synagogue on Mohegan Drive in West Hartford, the school is now housed in the renovated former public school building on s on Buena Vista Road in West Hartford. The school now provides a dual Jewish/secular education to students at the early childhood, elementary, and middle school levels.
Anniversaries; Board of Directors; Buildings, Hartford; Conservative Judaism; Education; Emanuel Synagogue; Jewish Education; New Americans; Newsletters; Playgrounds; Solomon Schechter Day School
- Series I: A-M
  - Anniversaries, undated
  - Awards and Honors/, undated
  - Awards and Honors/Newspapers clippings, undated
  - Board of Directors, undated
  - Board of Directors/Planning/Schechter High School planning, 1988-1989
  - Buildings/Buena Vista Road, 1984-
  - Buildings/Playground, undated
  - Education Programs/Adult Programs, undated
  - Education Programs/School Programs, undated
  - Education Programs/School Programs/Graduations, undated
  - Events, undated
  - Financial information, undated
  - Founding, 1971
  - Fundraising Activities, undated
  - Historical highlights, undated
  - Miscellaneous, undated
- Series II: N-Z
  - New Americans, undated
  - Newsletter/Alumni News, undated
  - Newsletter/Netivot Schechter, 1982-1983, undated
  - Newsletter/Schechter Days, 1989
  - Newsletter/Twenty-Something, 1991-
  - Newspaper clippings, 1970s
  - Newspaper clippings, 1980s
  - Newspaper clippings, 1990s
  - Newspaper clippings, 2000s
  - Open House, Recruitment, Enrollment, undated
  - Publicity/Promotional Brochures, undated
  - Silver Family, undated
  - Staff Members, undated
  - Strategic Planning, undated